## **Kenneth Rosales**

### Sr. Software Engineer

As a seasoned Senior Software Engineer boasting more than 6 years of immersive experience in the full software development lifecycle, I have consistently upheld a track record of exemplary performance while playing a pivotal role in driving the triumph of numerous projects within the software industry. My proficiencies extend beyond the realm of technical expertise, encompassing a robust foundation of both soft and technical skills that have been meticulously honed through dedicated training in the field of software engineering.

Contact Information kenneth1870@hotmail.com **Address** Heredia, Costa Rica Phone +506-7113-9550 Date of birth Jul 18, 1996 **Nationality** Costarricense Link

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kenne

th-rosales-71a2a46b/

## Experience

San José, Costa Rica Aug 2022 - Aug 2023

- Sr. RoR Engineer | Sr. Software Engineer Mismo

  - · Led project planning, scope definition, and requirements gathering.
  - Assembled and managed cross-functional teams.
  - Implemented Agile methodologies and conducted code reviews. Maintained regular client communication.
  - frameworks like Ruby on Rails and Express.js to build scalable and independent components of a larger application. Working with databases like MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB to store and retrieve data

· Designing, developing, and maintaining micro-services using Ruby and NodeJS with

- from Ruby applications. Collaborating with front-end to integrate Ruby code with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- using Typescript, ReactJS, Next.js for creating interactive and user-friendly interfaces. · Writing unit tests, integration tests, and performing debugging to ensure the reliability
- and functionality of Ruby code. · Implementing inter-service communication patterns such as RESTful APIs, message
  - queues, or event-driven architectures to facilitate communication between micro-
- · Contributing to open-source projects in the Ruby community by submitting bug fixes,
  - new features, or documentation improvements. Building and maintaining Ruby and Python applications that handle high traffic and
  - large datasets efficiently, ensuring scalability as the user base grows. Setting up and automating continuous integration and deployment pipelines for Ruby
  - and Python applications, streamlining the development and deployment processes.
- Experience with AWS using S3, EC2, RDS, CloudFront, ElasticCache, CloudWatch... Environment: Ruby on Rails 7,6, HTML, SASS, CSS, AJAX, JSON, Linux, RESTful, MySQL,
- PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Rspec, Cucumber, Capybara, React, git, Jenkins,

AWS, RSpec, Rubocop, Kubernetes, Docker, Node.JS, Express.js Sr. RoR Engineer | Sr. Software Engineer

San José, Costa Rica Jun 2021 - Aug 2022

Pixel506

## · Initiated project and defined scope and platforms.

- · Collaborated with design and backend teams. · Guided technology stack selection and coding standards.
- · Ensured code quality through automated testing. Implement clean and scalable APIs and data models using Ruby and Node.js
- · Requirements and Design Review Documents to develop Test Plan for projects involved and wrote Test Scripts for positive, negative, edge cases.
- · Perform prototyping, system analysis, development, and maintenance of systems. Work with QA as needed on automated testing. · Ensure code quality with one team (rspec, cypress, code reviews).
- · Ownership and responsibility for major aspects of product functionality from backend Work closely with stakeholders and peers to develop software that meets the
- business objectives of the organization. Using React.js and Ember.js to consume some micro-services

Design and implement clean and scalable APIs and data models

Environment: Ruby on Rails, HTML, SASS, CSS, AJAX, JSON, JQuery, Linux, RESTful, MySQL, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Rspec, Cucumber, Capybara, Ember, React, git, jenkis, AWS, postgresql, Js, Typescript, Ruby, Node.js

Jan 2019 - Jun 2021

San José, Costa Rica

· Led architectural design and team building efforts. · Ensured data security and compliance.

Sr. Fullstack Software Engineer

**Gorilla Logic** 

- Optimized data processing performance by 30%.
- · Maintained stakeholder communication. Developed Model View Controller (MVC) Architecture based Web applications in Ruby
- n Rails, BackboneJS, ReactJS and Vu · Creating new online products via Spree Commerce.
- Integrated payment system, Firebase real-time database platform, Spree e-Commerce platform. Manage controllers, Active Resources, Fixtures and Action View in Rails.
- Implemented AJAX driven UI Elements that were more agile and faster. Designed and developed RESTful style web services to manipulate dynamic datasets.

• Proficient in developing front-end systems using JavaScript, Bootstrap, tailwindcss.

- Implemented Authentication with Devise gem and configured the application according to the requirements.
- · Involved in modeling complex database table and relationships · Create micro-services using Ruby, Node.js, Python and Go.
- Experience in Agile Development, Git Hub, Amazon EC2, Amazon AWS and Heroku. Proficient in developing front-end systems with JavaScript, SASS, JS, Backbone JS
  - SCIM. Experience with cypressJS

Strong experience in using Web Services Technologies like SOAP, XML, SAML and

Environment: Ruby 2,3,4, Rails 5, Rails 6 beta, Amazon S3, Unicorn, MongoDB, Mac OS X, ImageMagick, RMagick, RSpec, Cucumber, XHTML, AJAX, Git, Capistrano, JavaScript,

JQuery, XML, XSL, SOAP, SAML, SAML, Shell Script/Unix, MySQL, React, Backbone, vue, node, Go, python, Node.js, Express.js Mid. Software Engineer

San José , Costa Rica May 2018 - Jan 2019

> · Communicating with the customer to design solutions. Implemented and enhanced CRUD operations for the applications using the MVC

and Bootstrap CSS.

Mismo

- Model View Controller architecture of Rails framework and Ruby conducting code reviews
- Database modeling and design. Involved in developing and implementation of the web application using Ruby on Rails. · Used Restful API to gather sales related data for products.
- Created custom angular filter function for parsing the data to users in a appropriate way.
- Created different modules like services, filters and directives using angularJS framework also using Node.js and Express.js Utilized functional JavaScript and DOM structure to implement various functionalities.
  - Working with Ruby gems and mongoDB adapters. Created Restful http services to Interact with UI(angularjs).
- Giving maintenance to the solution components for other projects. Environment: Ruby 2, Rails 3/4, Amazon S3, Unicorn, MongoDB, RSpec, Cucumber, HTML, AJAX, Git, Capistrano, JavaScript, JQuery, XML, angular.js, Node.js and Express.js.

Mid. Software Engineer **Geeks Technologies** 

· Good understanding of the syntax of the Ruby language Knowledge of RoR and

San José, Costa Rica Jan 2017 - May 2018

> libraries (Resque or RSpec) Knowledge of OOP Front-end technologies such as JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3 Familiarity with automated testing, continuous integration Experience in handling and developing

 Knowledge of Mocking, MVC, RESTful Ability to integrate multiple data sources and databases into one system Knowledge

of basic design principles for an app · Skilled at code versioning tools such as Git.

- Enthusiasm for emerging technologies and methods Pragmatism, reliability, and curiosity Excellent written and spoken communication skills
- Linux, SOAP, SQL Server, Shell Script/Unix, Web Sphere, CSS, react Jr. Web Developer

FoundationLab LLC Assisting the web development team with all aspects of website. Assisting with the testing and maintenance of backend and front-end applications.

Brainstorming new tech applications such as digital storage and mobile technology.

Environment: Ruby 2, Rails 4, XML, Action Script, AJAX, Java Script, JSON, XML, XSL,

Boston, USA Jan 2016 - Jan 2017

> Collaborating with developers to implement new web features. Keeping up-to-date with the latest technology and programming trends.

Using user feedback to identify and correct problems with a client's website. Environment: Ruby 2, Rails 3/4, XML, Action Script, AJAX, Java Script, JSON, Linux, SQL Server, Shell Script/Unix, Web postgresql, CSS, Git

Time Management

Languages

**English** 

Advanced

**Spanish** 

Native

# Soft Skills

Education

Heredia, Costa Rica Feb 2014 - Dec 2017

Good Communication Skills/Teamwork

Problem-Solving

Collaboration

Work Ethic

Continuous Learning

Flexibility/Adaptability

Creativity

Professionalism

Bachelor's Degree: Systems Engineering

Universidad Nacional De Costa Rica(UNA)

Certifications & Courses • 6th edition OWASP Latam Tour (04/2017 - 04/2017) Assistant 6th edition for OWASP latam tour 1st edition Rails Girls CR (10/2017 - 10/2017) Logistics, development and being a mentor.

Leadership

Tech Skills

## SQLite, MariaDB, Cassandra, Redis) · API Development and Integration (REST, GraphQL)

**Back-End Technologies:** 

**Front-End Technologies:** 

· Angular.js, React.js, Vue.js, Ember.js · Web Development (HTML, CSS, SASS, LESS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS) · Responsive Design and UI/UX Principles

• Go, Python, Node.js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Express.js, Django

Database Management (PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server,

Database Management: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server,

Agile Methodologies: Scrum, Kanban

QA: Manual Testing, Automation (Cypress.js, Cucumber)

DevOps:

Version Control: Git

SQLite, MariaDB, Cassandra, Redis

CI/CD: Jenkins, Travis CI, CircleCI, GitHub Actions Containerization and Orchestration: Docker, Kubernetes

Cloud Platforms: AWS, GCP, Azure

Infrastructure as Code (IaC): Terraform

Logging and Analytics: Grafana, New Relic, Datadog Collaboration Tools: Slack, Jira, Microsoft Teams, Zoom, Trello